Hi, welcome to session 18,
嗨，欢迎来到第 18 节课，
in this session, we're gonna talk about Jazz,
在这节课中，我们将谈论爵士乐，
one of my favorite subjects,
我最喜欢的话题之一，
how to play Jazz,
如何演奏爵士乐，
how to incorporate Jazz into your playing,
如何将爵士乐融入到你的演奏中，
how to get that warm round Jazz tone,
如何获得温暖的圆形爵士乐音调，
we're also gonna talk about chord melodies, chord melody soloing,
我们还将讨论和弦旋律，和弦旋律独奏，
I did a little bit of that in the intro there,
我在导言中做了一些，
it's taking a melody and adding chords underneath it
这是一个旋律，并在它下面添加和弦，
to make a more impacting solo,
以产生更具冲击力的独奏，
talking about Jazzing up your chord progressions
谈论爵士化你的和弦进程，
or regular chord progressions using chord tones,
或常规的和弦使用爵士音调，
and we also learn some popular Jazz forms,
我们还学习一些流行的爵士乐形式，
like your major seventh chords, your minor seventh chords and your ninth forms.
比如你的大七和弦，小七和弦和九和弦。
In the how music works section,
在音乐如何运作的部分，
we're gonna learn about ninth what they are,
我们将学习第九在音乐中是什么，
in music in, in understanding music,
在理解音乐方面，
what are ninth, what are eleventh, what are thirteenth.
什么是第九音，什么是第十一音，什么是第十三音。
What a great topic,
多好的话题，
we're gonna have a lot of fun today,
我们今天会玩得很开心的，
let's go ahead and get started.
让我们继续并开始吧。
Okay, Jazz guitar playing is such a great and creative way
好的，爵士乐吉他演奏是一种很棒的创造性的方式，
to add dimension into your playing,
可以为你的演奏增加维度，
so many different things can happen with Jazz
爵士乐可以发生很多不同的事情，
in harmonically with what's going on with the music,
与音乐发生的事情和谐一致，
rather than going just beyond the normal C G and D, that everybody plays,
不是仅仅超越每个人都演奏的正常的 C G D ，
you throw in some jazz chords,
你加入了一些爵士乐和弦，
it really adds some dimension you're playing.
它增加了你演奏的维度。
Now let's talk about some Jazz guitars,
现在我们来谈谈爵士乐吉他，
I'm playing on a Gibson ES335 right here,
我弹奏的是吉普森的 ES335 ，
very common in guitar,
在吉他中很常见，
you can do a lot of different styles
你可以做很多不同的风格，
and it works real good for Jazz,
它对爵士乐真的很有效，
it's got these humbucker pickups,
它有一些低音炮的拾音器，
which work real good for Jazz,
非常适合爵士乐，
there's also an ES175,
还有一款 ES175 ，
which is a thicker model
这是一个更厚的型号，
and that gets a little bit more of a rounder Jazz tone.
它得到一点更圆润的爵士乐音调。
Okay, let's talk about tone for a minute,
好的，我们来谈谈音调，
what makes a good Jazz sound for guitars,
什么能为吉他带来好的爵士乐声音，
well, you don't want anything too bright,
你不会想要太明亮的，
so generally,
所以，一般来说，
the first thing I do,
我要做的第一件事，
if I want to play Jazz,
如果我想演奏爵士乐，
as I go down to the amp
我调低扩音器的音量，
and I crank up the base a little bit,
把基本音调高一点，
I usually bring back, roll off some of those highs a little bit as well,
我通常会，也会从一些高音中恢复过来，
get a little bit more of a warmer, fatter tone.
得到更多的更温暖，更丰满的语气。
Sometimes I'll go over here to my tone knob
有时我会到我的音调旋钮前，
and I roll the tone back a little bit as well,
我也会把音调往后倒一点，
that helps in taking a little bit of that edge off the sound,
这有助于减少一点声音的边缘，
that's part of getting that Jazz tone,
这是获得爵士乐基调的一部分，
it's just taking that edge off the sound,
它只是把声音的边缘去掉了，
you don't want it harsh,
你不会想要它的刺耳的，
as harsh as it is in rock playing.
就像摇滚乐一样刺耳。
Okay, so that's, that's some secrets to getting a good Jazz tone.
好的，这是获得一个好的爵士乐音调的一些秘诀。
Also, the type of pick is helpful on that,
另外，拨片的类型对这一点也很有帮助，
you want something that's kind of fatter and rounder than a normal pick,
你想要一张比普通拨片更丰满和圆润的拨片，
it's a little bit thicker,
它有点厚，
its you at least a heavy pick,
至少是一个重的拨片，
when you do Jazz stuff,
当你演奏爵士乐时，
I have, I have another one here that I use a lot as well,
我这里还有一个，我也经常用到，
you see, it almost has no point on it at all,
你看，它几乎没有点，
it's just such a round thick
这简直就是又圆又厚，
and that's what you need guitar, for Jazz guitar playing.
这就是你做爵士吉他演奏所需要的。
Okay, now let's talk about chord melodies,
现在让我们来谈谈和弦旋律，
this is one thing that they use a lot in Jazz chord playing,
这是在爵士乐和弦演奏中经常使用的东西之一，
okay, what do I mean by chord melodies,
好的，我说的和弦旋律是什么意思，
well, here's the idea,
好的，我的想法是这样的，
you have your melody,
你有你的旋律，
your single note melody up on top,
你的单音符旋律在上面，
and then I'm going to try and squeeze in all of the chord tones
然后我要试着把所有的和弦音调都挤进去，
for the appropriate chords underneath that chord melody.
在和弦旋律下面找到合适的和弦。
Let's look at that first example in your book,
让我们来看看你书中的第一个例子，
the regular melody goes like this.
通常的旋律是这样的。
Okay, that would be a good Jazz little lick there,
好的，这是一个很好的爵士乐小片段，
now if I want to put chords underneath it,
现在，如果我想把和弦放在它下面，
I kind of go something like this,
我有点像这样，
ready go,
准备，开始，
now I just added a Cmaj7,
现在我刚加入了 Cmaj7 ，
we're gonna talk about those forms here in a second,
我们马上就会讨论这些形式，
but I added a Cmaj7 and an Emaj7 underneath it
但我在下面加了 Cmaj7 和 Emaj7 ，
to kind of give it a little bit of texture underneath,
让它下面有一点质感，
it makes a little bit more creative.
这会让你更有创意。
Let's look at that second example,
让我们看一下第二个例子，
okay, just the normal melody is like this,
好的，正常的旋律是这样的，
ready, go,
准备，开始，
okay, so now throw some chords on it,
好的，现在把一些和弦放在它上面，
comes out to be,
出来会是这样，
see how that works,
看到这是怎么工作的，
you just want to make sure you're adding chords to the notes
你只是想确保你在音符中添加和弦，
and where they appropriately come in the song,
以及它们在歌曲中出现的适当位置，
and sometimes you have to kind of play around with the fingering of your chord,
有时你不得不拨动一下你的和弦，
if your chord like the Cmaj7 usually goes down to this G,
如果你的和弦 Cmaj7 通常会到 G ，
but I just needed it down to the E,
但我只是需要它到 E ，
so I just use it where I need it,
所以我只在我需要的地方用它，
I just go down the E,
我只是到 E ，
I don't go all the way through the chord.
我不会一直走到和弦。
Another thing they do a lot in jazz is they do,
他们在爵士乐中做的另一件事是他们做，
West Montgomery was the Jazz guitar player that started,
West Montgomery 是爵士吉他演奏家的发起人，
they do octaves,
他们用八度音阶，
okay, so I just like here,
好的，就像在这里，
I am at the C at the eighth fret and the fifth fret,
我在 C ，在第八品和第五品上，
I use my first and my pinky there,
我在那里用我的食指和我的小指，
and I can play with my pick,
我可以用我的拨片弹奏，
and again, I'm deadening that inner string there,
再次，我让中间的弦变得麻木，
but when I go down to the fifth and the third string,
但当我降到五弦和三弦时，
I've got to go back to one and three
我必须回到食指和无名指，
and same thing with the sixth and the fourth,
第六弦和第四弦也是一样，
I gotta go one and three as well,
我也得有食指和无名指，
I can use it with a pick
我可以用拨片，
or I can use it with just my thumb,
也可以用拇指来用，
that's how West Montgomery did it,
West Montgomery 就是这么做的，
okay, so that's how West Montgomery did it.
好的， West Montgomery 就是这么做的。
Let me do those chord melodies that we did it earlier,
让我来做我们之前做过的那些和弦旋律，
this time I'm going to use octaves with it,
这一次，我将使用八度，
see how it changes the sound.
看看它是如何改变声音的。
Okay, so let's do the first example again,
好的，让我们再来一次第一个例子，
next example,
下一个例子，
takes a little practice to get the feel of using those octaves,
需要一些练习来获得使用这些八度的感觉，
but once you do,
但一旦你这样做了，
it's a real neat effect, that you can add into your playing.
它是一个真正的整洁效果，你可以添加到你的演奏中。
Okay, let me just touch on a couple of very common Jazz chord forms,
好的，让我来谈谈几种非常常见的爵士和弦形式，
that we haven't yet hit,
我们还没有讲到，
we've hit a bunch of open chords,
我们讲了一些开放和弦，
we've hit some barre chords,
我们讲了一些横按和弦，
now let's get on some of these Jazz chords,
现在让我们开始一些爵士和弦，
that involve a little bit more complex harmony,
这些和弦涉及到更复杂的和声，
your major sevenths, your minor sevenths, some ninth chords,
你的大七和弦，你的小七和弦，一些九和弦，
we'll talk more about what's involved in those ninth chords
我们更多地讨论九和弦所涉及的内容，
in our how music works section here in a second.
稍后在音乐工作原理部分。
But let me just show you some of those forms,
但让我向你们展示其中的一些形式，
in Jazz, you generally don't want to have open strings,
在爵士乐中，你通常不想有开放的弦，
you wanna have movable chords,
你想要有可移动的和弦，
they don't always have to be barre chords,
它们不一定总是横按和弦，
but they do have to be movable chords,
但它们必须是可移动和弦，
it, it just doesn't get that Jazz sound when you have open strings.
当你有开放的弦的时候，它就不会有爵士乐的声音。
Okay, so let's look at some of those main, major seventh forms first,
好的，所以让我们先来看看那些大七和弦形式，
on the sixth string, the form that I use all the time is this for an Fmaj7,
在第六弦上，我一直使用的形式是 Fmaj7 ，
again, you're muting that fifth string
再次，你把第五弦静音了，
and I don't play that highest six, first string, excuse me,
而我没有弹奏最高的六弦，一弦，抱歉，
now if I wanted one based off of a fifth string,
现在，如果我想要一个基于第五弦的，
I've got this very common Bmaj7 form right there,
我有这个非常常见的 Bmaj7 ，
I use it all the time,
我一直在用它，
anytime you're playing Jazz,
任何时候你演奏爵士乐，
that's one of my key chords,
那都是我的关键和弦之一，
another one is switch my fingers around a little bit
另一个是稍微交换一下手指，
and I have a Bmaj7 there,
我有 Bmaj7 ，
remember that diamond is the pivot note of those movable chords,
记住，钻石符号是那些可移动和弦的枢轴音符，
so I can move it up to here to Cmaj7 Dmaj7,
所以我可以把它移到这里，到 Cmaj7 Dmaj7 ，
okay, look at that,
好的，看看它，
that next form a Dmaj7 still based off the fifth string,
下一个模式 Dmaj7 仍然基于第五弦，
this time I'm pivoting off of that pinky though,
这次枢轴音符在小拇指这里，
okay, major, seventh chord.
好的，大七和弦。
Okay, now there's a couple of them,
好的，现在有几个，
couple of them that you can base off of the fourth string as well,
有几个，你也可以从第四弦开始，
which I use that quite a bit,
我经常用到，
this would be like an Emaj7,
这就是 Emaj7 ，
you got barre all three strings here with your third finger.
你用你的无名指横按这三根弦。
Okay, next one is a Gmaj7,
好的，下一个是 Gmaj7 ，
where is the G in this Gmaj7, right there,
这个 Gmaj7 中的 G 在哪里，就在那里，
and you end up having the seventh pitch up at the top.
你有第七个音高在最高位。
Okay, so those are what, six different major seventh forms,
好的，这是六个不同的大七和弦形式，
that's just about all the major seventh forms that I ever use,
这就是我用过的所有主要的大七和弦形式，
is in those six forms,
都是在这六种形式中，
so get those underneath your fingers
所以，把它们放在你的手指下，
and you'll be able to go a long way in playing Jazz,
你就能够在演奏爵士乐方面走得很远，
because they use an awful lot of major seventh chords.
因为它们使用了非常多的七大和弦。
Let's take look at, take a look at the next batch, some minor seventh chords,
让我们来看看下一批，一些小七和弦，
now, we've already found a couple of those,
现在我们已经找到了几个这样的，
when we were back doing our barre chords,
当我们回到我们的横按和弦的时候，
way back in the earlier sessions, probably session seven or so.
在前面的课程中，很可能是第七节。
Okay, so we're going to talk about some different forms that are minor seven forms,
好的，我们将讨论一些不同小七和弦形式，
let me just go through them real quick,
让我快速看一遍，
we have an Fm7,
我们有 Fm7 ，
that one's a little tough to grab right down here,
在这下面按起来有点困难，
some guys just do it like this,
有些人是这样做的，
Fm7, big barre chord,
Fm7 ，大横按和弦，
and here's a real common Cm7,
这是一个非常常规的 Cm7 ，
right there again, second finger is that C,
就在那里，食指是 C ，
maybe a little bit of a stretch the first time you tried,
你第一次试的时候可能有点拉扯，
but I use that one all the time,
但我一直都在用那个，
and of course, this guy Cm7 there,
当然，还有这个 Cm7 ，
which you've already been introduced, when we were doing our fifth string barre forms.
我们在做第五弦横按和弦形式时已经介绍过了。
Okay, so we got major sevenths, we've got minor sevenths,
好的，所以我们有大七和弦，我们有小七和弦，
I did on those major sevenths, I did throw down there in your book,
我在书中提到的大七和弦，
you've got some open major seventh chords that you can use in different forms,
你可以用不同的形式来使用一些开放的大七和弦，
wouldn't sound as great with Jazz,
在爵士乐中听起来不是很棒，
but you can use them in other styles of playing that you may need to do.
但你可以把它们用在其他你可能需要的演奏风格上。
I also want to touch on a couple more, ninth chords,
我还想再谈几个，九和弦，
okay, here's a good one,
好的，这是一个很好的，
based off of the fifth string and pivoting off the fifth string,
以第五弦为基础，以第五弦为轴心，
a C9, where's that C on that second finger,
C9 ，它的 C 在食指上，
I don't play,
我不弹奏，
It's just the inside four strings,
它只是里面的四根弦，
so I don't play the sixth string or the fifth first string,
所以我不弹第六弦或第一弦，
so an Eb9 would be there.
所以 Eb9 在这里。
Now there's one off of the sixth string, which is an A9,
现在这个在第六弦上，这是 A9 ，
which is a real pretty chord, I use this one a lot too,
这真是一个很好的和弦，我也经常用这个，
again, I'm muting that fifth string,
再一次，我将第五弦调成静音，
so you can't hear him
所以你听不到他的声音，
and I don't play the last string,
我也不会弹奏最后一根弦，
if I did, it would end up changing into a thirteenth chord,
如果我这样做，它最终会变成十三和弦，
but that's an A9, C9, A9
但这是 A9 C9 A9 ，
and those are just some common forms for that.
这些只是一些常见的形式。
Okay, now let's talk about Jazzing up your chord progressions,
好的，现在让我们来谈谈爵士和弦进程，
well, one of the easiest thing to do is add color tones,
好的，最简单的方法之一就是添加音色，
so if I'm, if it's a C chord that I'm looking at,
所以如果我看的是 C 和弦，
I can always add a color tone,
我总是可以添加一个音色，
well, what is a color tone,
那么，什么是音色，
color tones are tones that are added to the chord,
音色是添加到和弦上的音调，
still based off of the major scale,
仍然基于大调音阶，
so a C triad is C E G,
所以 C 三和弦就是 C E G ，
and the major seventh tone that would be that extra B,
大七和弦音色是额外的 B ，
one of the color tones, would be like your ninth eleventh and thirteenth,
一种音色是九、十一、十三，
now, which would be a D, would be the ninth,
现在，这将是一个 D ，将是第九个，
so, a Cmaj9 would be C E G B D,
所以， Cmaj9 应该是 C E G B D ，
one way to jazz up chord progressions is
一种让和弦进程变得更加爵士化的方法，
just by throwing extra color tones in there,
就是在那里加入额外的音色，
kind of gives it a sweeter sound,
让它听起来更悦耳，
so instead of C and an Am, let's say and a Dm and a G,
所以不是 C Am Dm 和 G ，
well, let's say I'm playing jazz,
好的，假设我在演奏爵士乐，
well, maybe I want to do a Cmaj7,
也许我想做 Cmaj7 ，
maybe I want to do an Am11,
也许我想做 Am11 ，
maybe a Dm9,
也许 Cm9 ，
maybe a G9,
也许是 G9 ，
something like that,
像这样的东西，
okay, just gives it a different color.
好的，只是给它一种不同的音色。
Let's go through a couple of progressions
让我们看几个进程，
and see what are some other things that we can do to Jazz up our progressions,
看看我们还可以做些什么来让进程变得更爵士化，
one of the things that we can do,
我们还能做的一件事，
other than adding color tones,
除了增加色调之外，
is adding what's called a ii-V progression,
是增加所谓的 ii-V 进程，
ii-V are used a lot in in Jazz harmony all over the place,
ii-V 在爵士乐的和声中经常被使用，
what do I mean by that,
我这么说是什么意思，
well, remember a couple of sessions back,
还记得之前的几次课程，
we talked about the harmonized major scale,
我们谈到了和声的大调音阶，
let's review,
我们来复习一下，
if I'm in C,
如果我在 C 中，
the first chord is, C major, C E G,
第一个和弦是 C 大调， C E G ，
the second chord is D F A,
第二个和弦是 D F A ，
and that ends up being a Dm chord,
最后是 Dm 和弦，
that would be our two chord,
那将是我们的第二个和弦，
it's a minor chord,
这是一个小调和弦，
if we jump up to the fifth,
如果我们跳到第五个，
our five chord would be a G B and D,
我们的第五个和弦将是 G B D ，
and that's back to a major chord,
这就回到了一个大调和弦，
so in any key,
所以在任何调上，
If I want to get to that key,
如果我想拿到那个调，
I just throw a two and a five in
我只需投入一个 2 和一个 5 ，
and it'll get me to whatever key I'm going in.
它就会把我带到任何我要进入的调。
Let's take a look at that first example,
让我们看一下第一个示例，
you've got two chords there,
你有两个和弦，
you've got a Cmaj7 going into an Fmaj7,
你有 Cmaj7 进入 Fmaj7 ，
pretty common progression,
非常常见的进程，
Fmaj7,
Fmaj7 ，
now that's, that's pretty good,
现在，这是非常好的，
but we can, let's see if we can Jazz it up
但我们可以看看是否可以使它更爵士化，
by using the ii-V of the key that we're going to.
通过使用我们想要的调的 ii-V 和弦。
So the first measure stays the same, Cmaj7,
所以第一小节保持不变， Cmaj7 ，
and then, but look, I still have that Fmaj7 in bar three,
但是看，我仍然在第三小节中有 Fmaj7 ，
but in bar two I'm adding the ii and the V,
但在第二小节，我加了 ii 和 V ，
to right before in the key of F, right before that F chord,
就在那个 F 和弦之前，
not the ii V in C,
不是 C 中的 ii V ，
but the ii V of the chord that I'm going to,
而是我要去的和弦中的 ii V ，
have the key that I'm going to,
我要去的调，
which ends up being a Gm and a C7.
最终是 Gm 和 C7 。
Let's hear how that changes the sound a little bit,
让我们来听听这是如何改变声音的，
ready go,
准备，开始，
gave it a whole lot more color there, didn't it,
给了它更多的音色，不是吗，
in the next exercise, I just do it again,
在接下来的练习中，我只需要再做一次，
we have the ii V going into the F
我们有 ii V 到 F ，
and then I throw another ii V, going back into that C,
然后我再抛出 ii V ，回到那个 C ，
if we're going to repeat it,
如果我们要重复它，
let's hear how that changes the sound,
让我们听听它是如何改变声音的，
ready, go,
准备，开始，
ii V in F,
F 中的 ii V ，
then ii V in C.
然后 C 中的 ii V 。
Now, [] have created a much more interesting chord progression,
现在，[]创造了一个更有趣的和弦进程，
by just adding ii-V,
只需增加 ii-V ，
another good simple rule that you can use is,
你可以使用的另一个很好的简单规则是，
whenever you have a dominant seventh,
当你有一个属七和弦，
this would be like a five chord,
这就像是一个五和弦，
a G7, C7 and F7, something like that,
G7 C7 F7 ，像这样的东西，
you can always play around with that seventh
你总是可以在七和弦上弹奏，
and add a bunch of stuff on that chord,
然后在那个和弦上添加一些东西，
you can add a ninth, you can add eleventh,
你可以加上第九个，你可以加上第十一个，
you can add a flat nine, you can add a sharp nine,
你可以加上一个降九，你可以加上一个升九，
you can add all kinds of things to that dominant seventh to give it extra color.
你可以在那个属七和弦中加入各种东西来赋予它额外的音色。
Let's take a look at those examples,
让我们来看看这些例子，
number four in your sheet,
你们乐谱上的第四个，
starts with a Cm7 to an F7 to Bbmaj7,
从 Cm7 到 F7 到 Bbmaj7 ，
let's say that's our base progression,
假设这是我们的基础进程，
now the next one,
现在，下一个，
I have a Cm7 and then I throw in an F9, and then a Bbmaj7,
我有 Cm7 ，然后 F9 ，然后 Bbmaj7 ，
so I've given it a little bit of color with that F9 there.
所以我给它加了一点音色，那里有 F9 。
Let's see what I did in the next one,
让我们看看在下一个中做什么，
oh wow, I looked added some color tones,
哦，我增加了一些音色，
Cm, I turned that into a Cm9,
Cm ，我把它转成了 Cm9 ，
the F7, I threw that all the way up to an F13,
F7 ，我把它转成了 F13 ，
the Bbmaj7 I turned him, turned him into a Bbmaj13,
Bbmaj7 ，我把它转成了 Bmaj13 ，
and then look what I threw in,
然后看看我放入了什么，
I threw in A G augmented,
我又加了一个 G 增强，
that would be like the V going back into that C,
这就像是 V 回到那个 C ，
that would be that form.
那就是那种形式。
Okay, so a couple new forms for you,
好的，所以几个不同的新形式，
but that's great,
但这很好，
learn all these forms,
学习所有这些形式，
write them down, get them underneath your fingers.
把它们写下来，把它们放在你的手指底下。
Let's try that last one again,
让我们再试一次最后一个，
see how much that changed the tone,
看看这在多大程度上改变了音色，
of the, of the song that you're trying to do,
对于你想要的这首歌，
that's really Jazz chord progressions,
那真的很爵士乐和弦进程，
and color tones, you can throw some ii-V in,
添加音色，你可以放入一些 ii-V ，
always [] around with that dominant seventh,
总是[]那个属七和弦，
you can get different colors there.
你可以在那里得到不同的音色。
Now let's go on to our how music works section,
现在让我们继续音乐工作原理部分，
I want to learn what exactly are those ninth and elevents and thirteenths.
我想知道那些第九，第十一，第十三个到底是什么。
In our how music works section today,
在我们今天的音乐如何工作部分，
I wanted to continue on learning how music is built together,
我想继续学习音乐是如何共同构建的，
how these chords are built together,
这些和弦是如何共同构建的，
we're almost through,
我们就快完成了，
last time we went over the major seven and dominant sevenths and minor sevenths,
上一次我们复习了大七和弦，属七和弦和小七和弦，
now we're just gonna kick that up one more third
现在我们要把再加上第三个，
and we're gonna add ninth,
我们要加上第九个，
and then another third on top of that is eleventh and thirteenth, thirteenth.
然后在上面的第三个是第十一个和第十三个。
Okay, well, let's talk about some confusion right there,
好的，让我们来讨论一下这里的一些困惑，
don't get lost in all the numbers,
不要迷失在所有的数字中，
there's not,
这里没有，
There's ninth, eleventh and thirteenth is what we're talking about,
有第九个、第十一个和第十三个，是我们所说的，
basically, there's the major scale,
基本上，这是大调音阶，
and then, if you can imagine another major scale right next to it,
然后，如果你能想象另一个大调音阶就在它旁边，
just like two octaves of a scale,
就像一个音阶的两个八度，
okay, so the ninth would actually be the second scale degree,
好的，所以第九个实际上是第二级，
so if I was in C, the ninth would be a D,
所以如果我在 C 中，第九个就是 D ，
see how that works,
看到这是怎么回事，
the eleventh is actually the fourth scale degree, which would be an F,
第十一个实际上是第四级，也就是 F ，
the thirteenth in C would actually be an A, same as the sixth,
第十三个是 A ，与第六个相同，
well, then why bother saying ninth, eleventh and thirteenth at all,
那么，为什么要费心说第九、第十一和第十三呢，
won't you just say second and fourth and sixth,
你不会只说第二、第四和第六吗，
well, when I say ninth, eleventh and thirteenth,
当我说第九、第十一和第十三时，
I am telling you, secret by code, that there's a seventh in there,
我是在告诉你，秘密是，这里面有第七个，
okay, so a C9 would be a C E G Bb and a D,
所以， C9 应该是 C E G Bb D ，
why, where I get that Bb from,
我从哪里得到 Bb ，
remember our seventh rule from a couple of sessions back,
记得我们之前几节课的第七个的规则，
everything, it's always a flatted seventh,
所有的，它总是一个降七，
unless it says the magic word, major seventh,
除非它说的是魔术单词，大七，
okay, unless it says the magic word,
好的，除非它说了魔术单词，
a C9 did not say have the word major in it,
C7 没有说有大调这个词在里面，
so, it's C E G Bb and D.
所以它是 C E G Bb D 。
Okay, see how that works,
好的，看到这是怎么回事，
a C2 would have a C D E and a G,
C2 会有 C D E G ，
but it wouldn't have that seventh in it,
但它不会有第七个，
so you see kind of difference,
所以你可以看到一些不同，
the ninth involves that seventh,
第九涉及到第七，
that's why it's called that,
这就是为什么它被称为这个，
what would be an F9,
那么 F9 是什么样的，
think about that at,
想想这一点，
what would it be, an F9,
F9 会是什么的，
well, let's figure it out,
让我们把它弄清楚，
it'd be an one, three, five, flat at seventh, because it didn't say major, then ninth,
它应该是 1 3 5 ， b7 因为它没有写大调，然后是 9 ，
so it'd be an F,
所以它应该是 F ，
it would be F A C Eb and G.
它应该是 F A C Eb G 。
What about a Dm9,
Dm9 是什么样的，
what would that one be,
那会是什么，
well, be one, flat three, five, flat seven, nine,
那是 1 b3 5 b7 9 ，
D F A C and E.
D F A C E 。
Let's do one more,
让我们再来一个，
what about a Bbmaj9,
Bbmaj9 是什么样的，
well, it'd be one, three, five, seven,
好的，它应该是 1 3 5 7 ，
it did say the word major in there,
它写着大调这个词，
so it would be a seven and nine,
所以它应该是 7 和 9 ，
so in Bb, that would be Bb D F A and then C,
所以在 Bb 中，是 Bb D F A C ，
that's how ninth chords work and how ninth chords are spelled.
这就是九和弦的工作方式和九和弦的拼写方式。
If we're to kick it up one more notch,
如果我们要把它再往上推一步，
we get into eleventh,
我们会进入第十一，
a couple of quirky things happen
会发生一些奇怪的事情，
when we add eleventh to it,
当我们加入第十一，
basically we just go up another third,
基本上我们只要加第三个，
so a C11 would be a C E G Bb D and now F,
所以 C11 应该是 C E G Bb D F ，
now, in theory land, I have that E and that F both in that chord,
现在，从理论上讲，我有 E 和 F 在这个和弦中，
but in practicality, whenever there's that eleventh in there,
但实际上，只要有十一和弦，
I don't include the third,
我就不包括第三个，
so it would, in practicality, when I'm actually playing it, I omit that third,
所以，实际上，当我演奏它时，我会省略第三个，
okay, so it be C G Bb D and F,
好的，所以它是 C G Bb D F ，
I just dropped that third,
我刚刚放弃了第三个，
because it would clash with the eleventh,
因为它会与第十一个相冲突，
see how that works,
看到它是如何工作的，
in F and F11 would be F C Eb G Bb.
在 F 中， F11 将是 F C Eb G Bb 。
Okay, what if I wanted an Fm11,
好的，如果我想要 Fm11 呢，
well, then I can still throw that third in there,
好的，那我还可以把第三个放进去，
I don't have that half step clash like I did before,
我没有像以前那样的半音冲突，
so it becomes F Ab C Eb G Bb.
所以它变成了 F Ab C Eb G Bb 。
Okay, see how important it is
好的，看到这有多重要，
to know your scales, know your keys,
知道你的音阶，知道你的调，
be able to spell these chords,
能够拼写这些和弦，
when we talk about soloing next section,
当我们谈到下一节的 solo 时，
this is gonna become real key in knowing what notes are in these chord chords
这将成为了解这些和弦中的音符是什么的关键，
as they're coming by on your piece of music.
因为它们会在你的音乐片段中出现。
Okay, the last one is thirteenth chords,
好的，最后一个是十三和弦，
wow, we have covered so many different types of chords,
哇，我们涵盖了这么多不同类型的和弦，
here's the last one,
这是最后一个，
okay, I just add one more third on top of that,
好的，我只需要在上面再加第三个，
so, a C13,
那么， C13 ，
well, let me back up,
好的，让我来回顾一下，
with the thirteenth, you also again, you omit that eleventh,
有了第十三个，你再次，省略了第十一个，
because it would clash with that third,
因为它会和第三个相冲突，
so if I'm in C,
所以如果我在 C 中，
C13 would be C E G Bb D F but I'm going to omit it and then A,
C13 是 C E G Bb D ， F 但我会省略它，然后是 A ，
see how that works,
看看这是怎么回事，
so, wow you've got seven notes or six notes in that chord,
哇，你的和弦中有七个音符或六个音符，
you're got an awful lot of notes that you're trying to keep track of,
你有太多的音符要记下来，
generally, with the thirteenth chord,
一般来说，十三和弦，
just remember it's the sixth scale step,
只需记住是第六音阶，
but you do have that flat seventh in there.
但你确实有降七的音阶。
Okay, let's talk about your assignment for this week,
好的，让我们来谈谈你这周的作业，
here's your assignment,
这是你的作业，
I want you to practice the new major seventh, minor seventh and ninth forms,
我要你们练习新的大七和弦、小七和弦和九和弦，
get them underneath your fingers,
把它们放在你的手指下，
be able to play them in different places on the neck,
能够在琴颈上的不同位置演奏它们，
practice working out a chord melody using the examples in your book,
使用书中的例子练习和弦旋律，
using the chord examples in your book,
使用你书中的和弦例子，
try adding some of the extra chords that we talked about
尝试添加一些我们讨论过的额外和弦，
and try to Jazz up those basic progressions,
并试图使这些基本进度变得更爵士化，
practice that West Montgomery Jazz octave style,
练习 West Montgomery 爵士乐的八度风格，
you can get a lot of good mileage out of
你可以获得很多不错的[]，
just playing octaves with that.
通过弹奏八度。
Don't forget to use those Jam Along CDs for a lot more practice,
别忘了使用 Jam Along CD 进行更多练习，
we'll go ahead and see you next time.
我们继续，下一次再见。
Okay, welcome to the workshop time,
好的，欢迎来到 workshop 时间，
here's where we get some of these chord forms underneath our fingers,
这是我们得到一些和弦形式在手指下面，
so that we can use them,
这样我们就可以使用它们，
they'll be in our musical tool belt,
它们会在我们的音乐工具带上，
and we can whip them out,
我们可以把它们拿出来，
when it's time to play a jazz song.
当我们演奏爵士歌曲的时候，
Okay, first it starts off with the major seventh forms,
好的，首先从大七和弦形式形式开始，
let's briefly review them,
让我们简要回顾一下它们，
in the sixth string, on the sixth string, we had that Fmaj7,
在第六弦上，我们有 Fmaj7 ，
remember, don't play that last string, don't play that fifth string,
记住，不要弹最后那根弦，不要弹第五根弦，
what if I wanted to play that Fmaj7 in a different place,
如果我想在不同的地方弹奏 Fmaj7 ，
let's say I wanted to Bbmaj7,
比如，我想要 Bbmaj7 ，
where would it be,
它会在哪里，
in that form right there,
在这个形式，
what if I wanted a Dbmaj7,
如果我想要 Dbmaj7 ，
Where would it be in that form,
在这种形式下，它会出现在哪里，
okay,
好的，
now remember some of the forms that we had on the fifth,
现在记得我们在第五弦上的一些形式，
based on the fifth string,
基于第五弦，
this Bmaj7 form,
这个 Bmaj7 形式，
let's jump that around a couple different places,
让我们跳过几个不同的地方，
what about an Ebmaj7 in that form,
在这种形式下， Ebmaj7 是什么，
what about Bmaj7,
Bmaj7 怎么样，
okay, I could use some of these other ones,
好的，我可以用一些其他的，
there's a Bmaj7 there,
那里 Bmaj7 ，
what about Ebmaj7 in another form,
以另一种形式， Ebmaj7 怎么样，
another form,
另一种形式，
six different forms,
六种不同的形式，
we should be able to play that Ebmaj7 in many different places on the neck.
我们能够在琴颈上的许多不同地方弹奏 Ebmaj7 。
Let's go for some minor seventh forms,
让我们来看一些小七和弦，
make sure we got those,
确保我们得到了那些，
okay, what about a Gm7,
好的， Gm7 怎么样，
well, I can do that all kinds of different ways,
我可以用各种不同的方法做到这个，
I can do this one,
我可以做这个，
all kinds of different options depending on where I want to go,
根据我想去的地方，有各种不同的选择，
if I'm playing up here,
如果我在这里弹奏，
I would probably want to grab these up here,
我可能会想在这里拿到这些，
there's no sense of me jumping away up here to this Gm7.
我就没有理由跳到这个 Gm7 。
Okay, what about an Abm7,
好的， Abm7 怎么样，
where would that be,
那会在哪里，
well, I can do that a bunch of different places,
我可以在很多不同的地方，
here or here, here, or even this one.
这里或这里，这里，甚至这个。。
Great, what about an F9,
好的， F9 怎么样，
can you find an F9,
你能找到 F9 ，
remember our ninth form,
还记得我们的九和弦形式吗，
well, here's our ninth form,
好的，这是我们的九和弦形式，
and then all I need to do is move it up to F
然后我要做的就是把它升到 F ，
and I've got an F9,
我就得到了 F9 ，
or I have my other F form too,
或者我也有我的另一个 F 形式，
I gotta get way up here at the top,
我得到顶端去，
F9 up there as well.
F9 也在上面。
What about a D9,
D9 怎么样，
well, he would be there,
好的，它会在那里，
or there, if you want to try and do,
或者这里，如果你想试着这样做，
if you want to try and do it that way.
如果你想试着这样做。
Let's play through some of the Jazz chord exercises that we have in your book,
让我们来弹奏一些在你书中的爵士和弦练习，
okay, the first one, we're going from a Cmaj7 to an Fmaj7,
好的，第一个，我们将从 Cmaj7 到 Fmaj7 ，
one, two, ready, go,
1 2 ，准备，开始，
Fmaj7.
Fmaj7 。
Let's do the second one,
我们来做第二个，
ready, go,
准备，开始，
here we add that ii-V, Gm7, C7,
这里我们加上 ii-V ， Gm7 C7 ，
do it again a little bit slower.
再来一次，慢一点。
Number three, two, ready play,
第三个， 2 ，准备，开始，
let's do that again,
我们再来一次，
now if I wanted to just Jazz that up a little bit,
现在，如果我想让它变得更爵士一点，
I could do something like this,
我可以做这样的事情，
I just added a couple little extra notes in there,
我只是在里面加了几个额外的音符，
use basically the same chord forms,
使用基本相同的和弦形式，
and we were able to get a little bit more mileage out of it,
我们能够从它中获得更多的里程，
almost making it a chord melody thing.
几乎使它成为和弦旋律。
Okay, let's do some of the dominant seventh ones,
好的，让我们来做一些属七和弦，
this would be exercise number four,
这将是第四个练习，
ready, go,
准备，开始，
do it again,
再来一次，
let's go to the next one,
让我们进入下一个，
two, ready, go,
2 ，准备，开始，
one more time.
再来一次。
Last one is that number six,
最后一个是第六个，
there we added a bunch of color chords on this color tone,
我们在这个音色上添加了一些音色和弦，
Cm9,
Cm9 ，
F13, or wait a minute, Cm9, we can do it down here, F13,
F13 ，或者等一下， Cm9 ，我们可以在这里做， F13 ，
Bbmaj13,
Bbmaj13 ，
G+7,
G+7 ，
see how that augmented fifth only wants to lean down,
看那个增加的第五个只想下来，
to that Cm9,
到 Cm9 ，
then the F13,
然后 F13 ，
I could stay right there if I wanted to.
如果我想的话，我可以呆在那里。
So I'm kind of making a little melody with those highest tones of those different chords,
所以我用不同和弦中的最高音调来制作一个小旋律，
here we go,
我们开始，
number six, ready, go,
第六个，准备，开始，
now I can Jazz up the rhythm a little bit,
现在我可以稍微爵士化节奏，
let's see what else we can do,
让我们看看我们还能做些什么，
I just kind of made those base notes come down a little bit.
我只是把那些基本音符降了一点。
Great, you can have a whole lot of fun with Jazz chord forms,
好的，你可以用爵士乐的和弦形式获得很多乐趣，
and it just adds about probably about ten or fifteen different chords into your repertoire,
它只是在你的曲目中增加了大约 10 到 15 个不同的和弦，
and it certainly gives you a whole lot more color that you can use.
而且它肯定会给你带来更多你可以使用的音色。
Okay, we'll see you next time.
好的，我们下次再见。